Kristopher Kohlmeier

Media Technologies

kristopherkohlmeier@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/kris-kohlmeier/ kristopherkohlmeier.com +1 (805)-276-4713

Media engineer with software development experience. Over three years of professional experience delivering technical solutions in medium-sized stage production environments. High familiarity with broadcast video technologies and editorial workflows for content creation.

Work Experience

Production Technology Assistant

Jun 2021 - Present

<u>Crossroads Church</u> | Camarillo

Operated as the main point person in charge of all A/V production and networking equipment weekly. Supported volunteer teams as well as staff members with A/V related tasks and training. Offered general IT support for on-site computers.

- Planned and executed over \$50,000 of value in A/V installs and upgrade projects.
- Onboarded new stage lighting console for production volunteers, offering training, on-call support, and programming when needed.
- Managed and maintained a 5 projector video system, and utilized projection mapping to create special effects for holiday stage productions.
- Repaired out of warranty stage lights and projectors to maintain low budgets and prolonge hardware lifespans.

Animation Technology Internship

Jun 2023 - Aug 2023

Skydance Animation Studios | Santa Monica

Three-month internship to work with and learn from five different technology departments in an animation studio. The five departments include: IT Help Desk, Cybersecurity, Systems/Network Engineering, Pipeline Engineering, and Media Engineering.

- Learned pipeline process for CG movies as well as networking infrastructure and media hardware requirements.
- Audited studio codebase, leveraging Rez API with a python script for the pipeline engineers.
- Created SOP for and assisted in the integration of a studio-wide printer system.
- Created a tracking document for all editorial hardware during studio location moves.
- Solved Jira Tickets for the general IT help desk and handled setup for a new fleet of computers

Projects

Story Development Software

Jan 2024 - May 2024

Prototype server and client that ingested storyboard panels and .EDL files to track editorial changes for a film in early production. Used as a senior project and developed using SQL and Python.

Core Skills

Stage Lighting Consoles, Live Audio Mixers, Multicamera Broadcast Equipment, Dante, Wireless Workbench, Projector Systems, Crestron, Python, C/C++, Javascript

Education

California State University Channel Islands

Jan 2021 - Jun 2024

Bachelor of Science Computer Science